ypowpo.org 2015-03-27

# YPO-WPO Privacy Policy

                          YPO-WPO Privacy Policy
This Privacy Policy applies only to the information collected through the website YPO-WPO
Exchange located at www.ypowpo.org (the “Exchange”). By visiting the Exchange, you accept
the practices described in this Privacy Policy for any information you provide and have
provided in the past through the Exchange. If you are uncomfortable with our policies and
practices, please do not provide any personal information to us through the site. As used in
this Privacy Policy, the terms “you” and “your” refer to each visitor to the site, and the terms
“we,” “our,” “us,” and “YPO” refer to Young Presidents’ Organization, Inc. or YPO-WPO.
YPO-WPO understands how important privacy is to our members. We are committed to
protecting your privacy and want to make sure that you understand how your personal information
is used.
What We Collect. When you apply for membership, we ask for basic information such as your
name, contact information and company information. We keep track of your participation in YPO or
WPO activities and member services so we can understand our members' interests and evaluate the
effectiveness of our offerings. We also collect demographic information from other sources to help
us learn more about member characteristics and needs. When you register with the Exchange, we
collect your name, email address, physical address and other autobiographical information, and you
can also provide additional information in your profile, such as your phone number, instant message
identifier, birthday, marital status, professional experience, education background, family members’
names and similar autobiographical information, photos, hobbies, and other interests. When you
visit the Exchange, we receive data about your interaction with various functionalities on the
Exchange, such as when you join a group and share information with other members. We also
receive information about you from other members, such as when they add you to a group or “tag’”
you. As explained in the Questions and Answers below, we may ask for additional information in
your visits to the Exchange. All of this information helps us better serve our members and improve
our programs.
Please note that by registering at www.ypowpo.org, or by otherwise providing
information on the site, you have given us your express and informed consent to transfer
the data that you provide to us to the United States and to process it in the United States.
Information Sharing. We share your personal information only with companies we have selected
to provide official YPO member services or support YPO-WPO operations. Our contracts with these
companies require them to keep the member information confidential, and allow them to use the
information only to offer the contracted services to YPO and YPO or WPO members. We may release
personal member information on the rare occasions when we are required to do so by law, or when
necessary or appropriate to comply with legal process or to protect or defend YPO and its members.
We do not sell or rent member information to telemarketers, mailing list brokers or any other
companies.
For more detailed information about our privacy practices, and about privacy on the Exchange,
please review the frequently asked questions below. To ask questions about your personal or other
membership information, please contact us at:
Phone, Mail or email:
YPO-WPO Member Services
600 East Las Colinas Boulevard, Suite 1000
Irving, Texas 75039
USA
membership@YPO.org
1.800.773.7976 ext.1441 or +1.972.587.1441
YPO-WPO Exchange Privacy: Questions and Answers

The following Questions and Answers address YPO-WPO Exchange privacy issues in more detail. We
want to make sure that you understand the types of information that are collected at YPO-WPO and
through the Exchange and the ways in which that information is used and protected. Specifically,
this privacy policy answers the following frequently asked questions:
1. Do I have to submit any personal information in order to use the Exchange?
2. Does the Exchange collect non-personal information, using "cookies" or otherwise?
3. How is this information used, and can I control its use?
4. Is any information shared with other companies or organizations?
5. What privacy rules apply when I "click" over to other web sites?
6. How does the Exchange protect security and confidentiality?
7. Will this privacy policy ever change?
8. Who can I contact with questions or comments about privacy issues?
1. Do I have to submit any personal information in order to use the Exchange?
If you want to take advantage of being a member of YPO or use of the member services available
on the Exchange, we will sometimes request information that allows us to identify you. If you use
the online form or paper application to join YPO or renew your membership, for example, we will
ask for certain information to process your application (name, company information, phone number,
mailing address, email address, family information, credit card number and other various pieces of
information). You will receive email newsletters and we may also ask for personal information when
you participate in other activities or services on the Exchange, such as surveys and event
registration.
We also have relationships with certain providers and vendors that we have selected and approved
to offer services and benefits on linked sites. On some of these sites, you may be asked to enter
personal information in order to take advantage of their services or programs. If you decide to
purchase services on the website of one of our member benefits service providers, the contracted
member benefit provider offering the services may ask for your name, member number, address,
and email in order to contact you about the services.
On the Exchange, you can create an autobiographical profile that will be visible to YPO and WPO
members and their spouse or partner or other family members who have been granted access to
members-only portions of the Exchange. The Exchange also provides forums, applications, and
functionalities that allow you to communicate and share information with other members, their
spouses or partners, and other family members. The information that you share with others can
then be copied or re-shared by them. When you use these social networking tools, you control what
information and how much information you share. You can also choose not to use these social
networking tools. The information you provide to YPO-WPO may reveal, or allow others to identify,
your nationality, ethnic origin, gender, age, religion and other aspects of your life. Supplying
information to YPO-WPO, including any information deemed “sensitive” by applicable law, is entirely
voluntary on your part.
Again, regardless of whether you are visiting the Exchange or an affiliated site, you do not have to
disclose any personal information if you do not want to. We are only interested in offering you
convenient services that match your interests and needs.
2. Does the Exchange collect non-personal information, using "cookies" or otherwise?
We also collect other types of information that do not allow us to identify your name, email address,
or other personal characteristics. This "non-personal information" includes the number assigned to
your computer whenever you access the Internet ("IP address"), and the type of browser you use.
None of this non-personal information allows us to identify or contact you. We use this information
to help us evaluate how the site is being used. By gathering this information, we can learn, among
other things, how many people visit the site, which pages are the most and least popular, and which

other web sites are the most frequent referral sources for YPO-WPO.
We may also assign a "cookie" to your computer in some situations. Like an IP address, a "cookie"
is a kind of online identification tag that allows us to recognize your computer each time you visit
the Exchange.
We currently use Google Analytics to capture the GUID (Globally Unique Identifier) for each user,
region or chapter, age range, gender and user type, although we may use other similar tools in the
future. The GUID is personally identifiable by YPO-WPO but not by Google. The information is stored
in the cookie Google places on the computer for web analytics. In addition, we use a cookie to store
the user login name when he or she chooses the “Remember Me” option on the login page. We also
use an authentication cookie that lets the site know the user has a valid login.
If a user disables session cookies, the site may not work. Users can only disable first party and third
party cookies.
3. How is this information used?
Our primary purpose in collecting this information is to provide you with the services you request,
provide you with customized content, allow you to interact with other members, and to evaluate
and improve other services that we offer now and in the future, both on the site and offline. As
explained above, for example, we ask for information so that we can process your membership
application, send you the email newsletters, and allow your use of the functionality on the site. We
may also use this information for other purposes. For example, we may review demographic
information, survey results, and statistical analyses regarding site usage in order to help us
evaluate, modify, and develop services that are likely to be of interest to our members.
On occasion, we will also use your membership information to send you information about special
member benefits and offers, and new features and groups on the Exchange. If you initiate
communications with other members through the Exchange, those communications will include your
name, email address or other communication identifier, and, if applicable, group information.
4. Is any information shared with other companies or organizations?
YPO-WPO takes seriously its responsibility to keep your personal information confidential and
private. We do not sell or rent any of our members' personal information to telemarketers, mailing
list brokers, or any other companies that are not offering YPO-endorsed services or benefits. As
explained above, we share member information with the limited number of companies that we have
selected to provide YPO-WPO member services. Like most organizations, we also hire companies to
provide certain administrative services that require access to member information, such as
processing address labels, managing databases, and sending mailings ("approved vendors").
We require all of these YPO-WPO service providers and approved vendors to hold member
information in confidence. These providers and vendors are contractually required to maintain the
security and confidentiality of all member information, and are prohibited from using that
information for any purpose other than providing the services specified in their contracts with YPO-
WPO. We may, at our discretion, audit and monitor these companies to ensure that the member
information is protected.
We may also disclose personal information when required to do so by law or when such action is
necessary or appropriate to comply with legal process served on YPO, to protect and defend the
rights or property of YPO, or to protect the personal safety of users of the site. We reserve the right
to contact the appropriate authorities in our discretion when visitors' activities appear to be illegal or
inconsistent with our policies.

5. What privacy rules apply when I "click" over to other web sites?
The site includes links to other web sites, some of which are operated by YPO-WPO service
providers or approved vendors, and some of which are not. Sites operated by YPO-WPO service
providers and approved vendors may also collect personal information, and may have their own
privacy policies that differ from, and are not covered by, this privacy policy. It is important that you
review any privacy policies on these sites carefully before you use any services or programs offered.
When you click to unaffiliated third-party sites, YPO-WPO is not responsible for, and has no control
over, the information collection or privacy practices of that site. It is important that you review and
understand the privacy policies posted on any linked sites you visit before volunteering any of your
personal information. These sites may also collect cookies, or allow third-party advertisers on their
sites to collect cookies. You can often find information regarding a site and its privacy policy on the
site's home page. If you cannot find or do not like a site's privacy policy, you may prefer not to do
business with, or offer information to, that site.
6. How does the site protect security and confidentiality?
In order to protect your personal information, we use technologies and processes such as
encryption, access control procedures, network firewalls, physical security and other measures.
These measures increase, but do not guarantee, the security and privacy of information traveling
to, from, and within the Site. Only our authorized employees, agents or independent contractors
carrying out permitted business functions are allowed to access personal information. Employees
who violate our privacy access policies may be subject to disciplinary actions, including termination
when appropriate.
In order to receive some services, we may require you to use a password to protect your
membership account from unauthorized access by others. You are responsible for maintaining the
secrecy of your unique password and account information, and for controlling access to your
communications on the site at all times. If you do allow others, including family or household
members, to access YPO-WPO members-only services through your personal password or to use
your membership account number, please understand that you are responsible for the actions of
those individuals. Please note that emails, instant messaging and similar means of communication
with other members are not encrypted, and we advise you not to communicate any confidential
information through these means.
7. Will this privacy policy ever change?
This privacy policy describes the types of information we currently collect, and the ways we use and
protect that information. If you are uncomfortable with our policies and practices, please do not
provide any personal information to us through the site. This Privacy Policy was last updated 16
August 2013.
From time to time, we may collect different types of information and use that information in
different ways - for example, when we add features or services to the Exchange. In these cases, we
may edit this policy to explain the new practices. Because protecting members' privacy is very
important to us, we do not expect major changes in policy. However, if we do make significant
changes in our practices, we will include announcements on the Exchange home page so that you
will know to review the revised policy. If you object to any changes, you may delete your account
by contacting us. By continuing to use the Exchange after notice of changes has been sent to you
or published on the site, you are consenting to the changes.
8. Who can I contact with privacy questions?
If you have any questions or comments about your member information or this privacy policy,
please send an email to exchangesupport@ypowpo.org. We will do our best to investigate any
question you may have and respond promptly to your concerns.
